Guide to the James L. Weil Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- April 1998 Acquisition, 1927-1980s; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  - Writings by Spencer Brown
    - "This Will Never Do," printed version, Chelsea, 1964 (Box 18)
    - "The Twilight of T. S. Eliot," printed version, The Ethical Outlook, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Other Material
    - Miscellaneous material, circa 1950s-1980s; 4 (Box 19)
- May 1998 Acquisition, 1978-1997; 1; (1 box)
  Organized into two subgroupings: Monthly Poems and Other Writings.
  The May 1998 Acquisition consists entirely of writings by Simon Perchik. The first subgroup consists of small numbers of poems written and organized by the months of the year, presented ("No. _ of 10 copies") in typescript, signed and with inscriptions from Perchik to Weil.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 560.
  - Monthly Poems
    - "January Poems", 1981-1997; 8 (Box 20)
    - "February Poems", 1982-1997; 8 (Box 20)
    - "March Poems", 1984-1994; 9 (Box 20)
    - "April Poems", 1982-1993; 11 (Box 20)
    - "May Poems", 1984-1994; 9 (Box 20)
    - "June Poems", 1979-1995; 10 (Box 20)
    - "July Poems", 1983-1994; 9 (Box 20)
    - "August Poems", 1981-1993; 7 (Box 20)
    - "September Poems", 1982-1990; 8 (Box 20)
    - "October Poems", 1983-1993; 8 (Box 20)
    - "November Poems", 1982-1996; 7 (Box 20)
    - "December Poems", 1984-1993; 6 (Box 20)
  - Other Writings
    - "December Poems: To The Photographs of John R. Milton", 1984 December (Box 20)
    - "Hauppauge Tales", 1978 June 30 (Box 20)
    - "The Milton Poems", 1992 September 17 (Box 20)
    - "Poems For a Winter", 1979 (Box 20)
    - "The Ramesh Poems", 1992 November 17 (Box 20)
    - "The Snowcat Poems", 1980-1981; 2 (Box 20)
    - "The Two Aprils Poems", 1989 April (Box 20)
    - "The Two June Poems", 1989 June (Box 20)
- February 2000 Acquisition, 1996-2000; 2; (2 boxes)
  Gift of James Weil, 2000.
  The February 2000 Acquisition includes correspondence, production files, and printed material by or relating to Weil. The correspondence, unsorted and largely still in envelopes, includes some scattered manuscript and printed material. There are letters from the many libraries to which Weil donated publications and from writers with whom he collaborated, including Cid Corman, Simon Perchik, Felix Stefanile, and Jack Stillinger, among others.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 17.
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1996-2000, undated; 15 (Box 21)
  - Production Files
    - For All We Know by William Bronk, 1997-1998 (Box 22)
    - Founding Fathers by James L. Weil, 1997 (Box 22)
    - "Gregory's Last Stand", 2000 (Box 22)
    - "Imperatives Composed For Bill's Voice", 1999 (Box 22)
    - Johnny Cake by Cid Corman, 1997-1998 (Box 22)
    - Joys & Wonders by William Bronk, 1996-1997 (Box 22)
    - Life Supports by William Bronk, 1999-2000 (Box 22)
    - Lines & Smudges by William Bronk, 1998-1999 (Box 22)
    - Literal Speech by William Bronk, 1997 (Box 22)
    - "Peter the Great", 1999 (Box 22)
    - This living hand, now warm and capable by John Keats, 1999 (Box 22)
    - Two Sonnets by Spencer Brown, 1999 (Box 22)
    - "When the Kingko Drops", 1998-1999 (Box 22)
  - Other Papers
    - Miscellaneous material, circa 1982-2000, undated; 9 (Box 22)
- January 2002 Acquisition, 1980-2001; 2.21; (3 boxes)
  Box 25 (videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Gift of James Weil, 2002.
  The January 2002 Acquisition also contains correspondence, production files, and other material. The correspondence, unsorted and largely still in envelopes, includes some enclosures, such as manuscripts, photographs, and printed ephemera. There are letters and cards from many ongoing collaborators, such as Jack Stillinger, as well as Theodore Enslin and Michael Peich.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 250.
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1989-2001, undated; 27 (Box 23)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 2000-2001, undated; 5 (Box 24)
  - Production Files
    - Christ's Entry Into Jerusalem and Other Facts by James L. Weil, 2001 (Box 24)
    - "Eichstetten", undated (Box 24)
    - Lines & Smudges by Cid Corman, 1999-2000 (Box 24)
    - Mann Gulch by James L. Weil, 2000 (Box 24)
    - The Puzzling of the Grammarian by Alexander Pope, 1999-2000 (Box 24)
    - Really by James L. Weil, 2000-2001 (Box 24)
    - Washday, and Others: Poems 1996-1998 by James L. Weil, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Wordsworth's Shaggy Dog by Jack Stillinger, 2000-2001; 2 (Box 24)
  - Other Material
    - Free Lunch, printed version, 1999 (Box 24)
    - "Ideas and Images: An Interview With Simon Perchik" (videotape), undated
    - "Menudo (1\85) \ Spencer Brown (from 3 10)-1\80, Free El Norte" (videotape), 1980, 1985
    - Miscellaneous material, 2000-2001 (Box 24)
    - Stamps, undated (Box 24)
  - Restricted Material
    - Ideas and Images: An Interview with Simon Perchik, 30 minutes, undated; YCALMSS825_0001; 1; 00:29:43 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002102317436)
    - Menudo, Spencer Brown (from 310)-1180, free El Norte, undated; YCALMSS825_0002; 1; 02:46:14 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002102317444)
- May 2005 Acquisition, 1964-2004; 2; (2 boxes)
  Gift of James Weil, 2005.
  The May 2005 Acquisition contains correspondence, production files, and other papers. Correspondents include Bob Arnold of Longhouse Publishers & Booksellers, Henry Lyman, David Giannini, Lyman Gilmore, Jack Stillinger, Pierre Ullman, and others.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 772.
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1999-2004, undated; 29 (Box 26)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1980-2003, undated; 6 (Box 27)
  - Production Files
    - The Barn Mother Loved To Paint by James L. Weil, 2002-2003; 2 (Box 27)
    - Bill's Room by Henry Lyman, 2002-2003 (Box 27)
    - The Fife by William Bronk, 1994-2001, undated (Box 27)
    - Gregory's Last Stand and Other Lasts by James L. Weil, 2000-2001 (Box 27)
    - "The Magic Flute", 2002 (Box 27)
    - "Mother's Figure of My Father", 2002 (Box 27)
    - On the Drawing of John Keats in Death by Rainer Maria Rilke, 2000-2002 (Box 27)
  - Other Papers
    - "50th" wedding party, 2003 (Box 27)
    - Bibliographic card file, 1964-1969, undated (Box 27)
    - Manuscript fragment, undated (Box 27)
    - Printed and other material, 1973-2003, undated; 3 (Box 27)
    - Travel material, circa 1992 (Box 27)
    - Writings by Others, 1994-2002, undated (Box 27)
- September 2005 Acquisition, 1992-2005
  The September 2005 Acquisition consists of a single autogaph letter to Weil from "Arleen" and a copy of Little, inscribed and presented by Weil to Pat Willis.
  Former call number: Uncat Za File 708.
  - Letter, 1992 October 26 (Box 27)
  - Little by James L. Weil, 2005 (Box 27)